￼Instillation	Everything needed to run Rcade can be installed from an install script located on Github. To download this scrip, go to https://github.com/thevoiceless/master-install/downloads. Choose to download as a zip or tar file. After extracting the the file, view the read-me for assistance. To run the install script from a terminal type "sudo ./master_install.sh". This install script will download all dependencies and files needed for Rcade to run. The list of dependencies can be found in the packages file that was extracted. This script will compile MAME which can take up to 45 minutes. The script does not handle anything related to the server code. To download that go to https://github.com/made2k/RcadeServer/downloads. You will need to download as either a zip or tar file and extract the files. For RFID Use:If you plan on using an RFID reader to log users in and out, you need to add the user to the dialout group on the computer. To do this, log in to the computer and go to System -> Administration -> Users and Groups. For the user, select Manage Groups and then add the user to the dialout group.SetupServerOnce you have downloaded the server code from Github you need to configure it for use with your database. Once you extract the folder, navigate into it and open the file  grails-app/conf/DataSource.groovy and fill your database information in the production environment. Open up Config.groovy in the same directory and near the the bottom of the file there is an environments code block with production as one of the elements. Uncomment this out and put the URL your server is hosted on as the grails.serverURL variable. Navigate back to the root of that directory and go into the SupportScripts directory. I had sent JC and Topher some support files that are needed to get things set up. Get the file PostToYammer.py and move it into the SupportScripts directory. This file will post high scores to Yammer for the company.Once those tasks are done it is time to package the web app into a war file for deployment. Navigate back to the root folder of the web app. Type "grails war" to package the contents into a war file that you can now deploy on a server.Open up the web app and log in as an administrator. By default the admin user name and password is admin and password. To change this go to the Users tab on the left side of the home screen. Click Admin then Edit. Here you can change your username and password. DO NOT change your role.On the User page you can also add new users. There is no functionality for non-admins but you can still add others nonetheless. You will need to assign others passwords and tell them to change it. Rcade Once you have installed Rcade, run the command: Rcade. This should not open the program but instead install some configuration files that we will edit. If the program does launch, press Escape to quit. Allowing Connection to the ServerNavigate to ~/.wahcade/confs/. Open up the DB-default.txt file and change the information so that it points to your server. The host is the address the server is running on. The user and password field in this file relate to the the database that the server is connected to. Once you are done editing that file check in the same directory for a file called authkeys. If it doesn’t exist create it otherwise open it. There should be one line in this file with the username and password of an administrator of the server. The format this line needs to have is: [username:password] (without brackets). This will allow Rcade to post to your web app with administrator privileges. After modifying that file open up the LDAP.txt file to put in information to allow Rcade to get informations about the employees allowing them to log in. The BIND_DN and BIND_PASS relate to a shared account for the LDAP server. You will need to get these from a systems administrator but use the rest of the information provided to get connected to the ReadyTalk system:LDAP_SERVER | ldap://zeus.readytalk.comUSER_BASE | ou=ReadyTalk Employees,dc=readytalk,dc=comUSER_FILTER | (objectClass=*)PAGE_SIZE | 10Setting Up MAMEOpen the file /etc/sdlmame/mame.ini. In this file configure the rompath to point to a directory containing your roms (or do a directory that will contain your roms). If you are happy with the default (.mame/roms/) leave it as is. Remember this path. You can configure artpath and the other optional paths if you have rom cover art that you would like to include. Scroll down a little under CORE OUTPUT DIRECTORY OPTIONS. Take note of the nvram_directory and hiscore_directory (by default they should me in $HOME/.mame.Get the file original_highscores.tar that was sent to JC and Topher and extract the contents. It's will extract two directories, "original hi" and "original nvram". In the $HOME/.mame directory if you don't have the directories "hi" and "nvram" create them and copy the contents from the originals into their respective folders. This will prevent false high scores being recorded to the server the first time you play. Tip: if this will be running on a less than stellar computer, change the option autoframeskip to 1 under CORE PERFORMANCE OPTIONS. This will automatically skip frames if the CPU is bogged down allowing for a more fluid gaming experienceSetting Up RcadeFrom the terminal type ‘rcade-setup’  launch the options for Rcade. Here you can select key bindings and other preferences. Click on the Emulators tab at the top and for the M.A.M.E. Emulator the Application path should be /usr/games/sdlmame. The List Generation field will allow you to tell MAME where your Rom's are stored. Make sure that the path to your roms is correctly displayed here. To add lists to the front end such as the most popular games and high score supported games, open the Lists field at the bottom of the menu. Add two lists. Call one of them something along the lines ‘Popular’ and for the list type select XML Remote. This will pull the most popular games from the server. For the other list, name it something like ‘High Score Support’ and in the list type select High Score Supported. This will allow a list of only games with high score support. Finally click on the Extra tab at the top and click the button on the right of the XML / Data File field to generate an XML file. Make sure you save the settings before you exit (File -> Save or Ctrl + s). You are now ready to play some games!(Optional) Portal Sound EffectsTo allow Portal sounds to play from the cabinet, extract the contents of the portal_sounds.tar file that was part of the files sent to JC and Topher into ~/.wahcade/confs/sounds. These sounds will play at random intervals while Rcade is running.FeaturesHigh ScoresRcade allows MAME to not only save your high scores, but also uploads them to a server for company wide competition. Each MAME cabinet that is connected to the server will send your high score to the server once you exit out of the game. MAME has a limitation in that it doesn’t save high scores until it is exited. Scores will be saved, but you must exit the emulator. Multiple high scores can be set before exiting the emulator and they will all be saved and uploaded. UsersRcade allows users to log in either manually or using their RFID cards they use to get into the building. By logging in Rcade is able to upload your high score to the server and associate it with you so that you can track all of your high scores. On the web-app you are able to see all of the games you’ve played and how you’ve done on them.Video ChatNo self respecting arcade cabinet that shares its score with a server would be without a way to talk to other cabinets. Rcade allows for video chat between multiple cabinets running Rcade. With a simple toggle button you are able to open up a feed into any other cabinets that are connected to the server. Custom ListsRcade has support for custom lists that users can create. It is recommended to have at least a Popular Games list as well as a High Score Support list (each of which is detailed in the setup instructions). The Popular Games list pulls the most popular games from the server and displays the games in a simple and non-cluttered list. Use lists to organize games how you want.